

Hemant Patkar Scrum Certified Full Stack Developer



Basic Information

Current Location: Mumbai

Marital Status: Married

Date of Birth: 27th July 1987



Contact Me

hemantpatkar.hsp@gmail.com

& 8082109966 / 7977070006

https://hemantpatkar.github.io



Professional Skills

- Google Cloud / Azure Cloud
- Angular 9
- C#/.net Core / MVC / OOPS
- Okta SSO / OIDC
- Microservices / WCF / Web API •
- MS SQL / LINQ / Entity Framework
- JavaScript / jQuery
- Scrum Agile /Jira / Confluence
- CSS / Bootstrap 4
- SOA / Docker / Kubernetes



Certifications

- Scrum Developer Certification
- **Azure Certification**
- **GNIIT Course from NIIT**

Domains Worked On

- **E-Commerce**
- Warehousing
- **ERP**
- **Human Resource Management**
- **Talent Management**



Interests

- **Monsoon Trek**
- **Playing Tabla**
- Watching Movie
- **Long Drives**
- **Listening Music**

Career Objective



An MCA postgraduate having 12 years of experience in multiple domains. Seeking a position to utilize my abilities and skills in the Information Technology Industry that offers me professional growth and challenging work environment while being resourceful, innovative, and flexible.



Project Experience

[March 2021 - Till Now] - 3 Years 2 Months

Capgemini as Full stack .net developer/Architect

- Microservice using .net core 6 with Angular as frontend.
- **Dynatrace** for application monitoring
- Azure Devops for Code Repo and auto deployment with Classic pipelines and YAML pipelines with docker images.
- Google Kubernetes for application hosting and scaling Technologies used - Angular 9, net core 6, MS SQL, Identity Server 4, Azure DEVOPS, Google Cloud, SOA, Docker, Kubernetes.



[Nov 2016 - March 2021] 4 Years 4 Months

Ingram Micro as Lead Software Development Engineer

- Implemented OKTA for login with OIDC implementation for ecommerce Enterprise SSO and mobile app.
- Microservice with ASP.net Core for Profile API with SAML used with Okta inline token to provide user information as a response to client application.
- Ecommerce Shopping Application with back office including SAP and Impulse Integration (MVC/Web API/WCF).
- Cisco Vendor Portal using MVC n-layer Architecture and APIs.
- Agile software development with Jira for all projects.



[Nov 2012 - Nov 2016] 4 Years

Big Sun Technologies as Senior Software Developer

- Warehousing System with integrated Financials (C#.net and SQL).
- Online Support portal and Ticket system (C# ASP.net and SQL).
- ERP (Finance, Stock and Production) (Strong Oops Concept with
- Data migration for Upgrading old systems (MS SQL Server).
- Human Resource Management with mobile app integration (C# Asp.net with Web Services).



[Dec2011 - May2012] (Internship) 6 Months

Arête Technologies for MCA final year project

Shopping Cart for Net Spider India using ASP.net and MS SQL



Education

2012 Master of Computer Applications, Mumbai University NCRD-Sterling Institute of Management Studies

2009 BSC in Computer Science, Mumbai University

Strengths & Skills

- Strong verbal & communication skills. Strengths include team spirit, the ability to learn new concepts and quest for knowledge.
- Motivation and enthusiasm with single pointed focus and aptitude to learn are additional strengths. Methodical approach to work with perfection.
- Will to work in harmonizing the company's goals with personal growth and provide pleasant work environment.
- Self-confident and Trustworthy.